# Ravi Teja Rajaboina 🔾 Featured

Software Engineer seeking DEVOPS roles in Software Configure, Management, Build with Continuous Integration and Application Deployment with GIT, Tomcat, Nginx, Maven, Jenkins, Artifactory, Oracle, MySQL, Shell, linux, Chef, Docker, AWS, Kubernetes



Current Designation: Software Engineer -DevOps Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Current Company: Genpact India Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Configuration Management, Build Management, Release

Management, Continuous Integration, Application Deployment, System

Administration, GIT, SVN, Tomcat, Nginx, Maven, Jenkins, Oracle, MySQL, Shell, Chef, Sonar Qube, Docker

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Involvement in IT industry comprising of LINUX, System Administration, Software Configuration Management (SCM), Build, Deployment and Release Management, Software advancement environment set up and Devops automation engineering with AWS Cloud Implementations also involved in oracle Apps consultant.

Provide assistance to clients with the implementation of configuration management, release management and process creation. Experienced in planning, installation, and administration of GIT on Linux and Windows platforms.

Have good Working experience on Linux, Windows platforms

Have good experience on agile methodology & software development process Experience in migrating applications/repositories from SVN environment.

Proficiency in SCM techniques - branching, merging, controlling, and monitoring code changes

Experience on build Tool Maven

Good experience on Build Tool Maven and CI Tools like Jenkins

## Work Experience

**Genpact India** as Software Engineer -DevOps Jul 2017 to Till Date

Involvement in IT industry comprising of LINUX, System Administration, Software Configuration Management (SCM), Build, Deployment, Release Management, Docker and orchestration with Kubernetes Software, advancement environment set up and Devops automation engineering with AWS Cloud Implementations also involved in oracle Apps consultant

**Birlasoft Pvt. Ltd.** as Associate Software Engineer Jan 2015 to Jul 2017

#Project 4:

Project Title : Risk Digitization
Client Name : GE Real Estate, USA
Designation : Associate Software Engineer
Duration : March2015 to July 2017

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=74669c04ffc3719a0f905a32d03c6da45a550c5642145f455645125e090f...

Description: This project is about comprehensive and consistent risk management process that markedly improves the business in terms of Capital Allocation, deal review & pricing, performance measurement and portfolio management. This Consistency project needs enhancements in various systems as Asset Management, Finance.

#### Responsibilities:

Worked on modifying the existing queries as per the new enhancements.

Doing unit testing of the code.

Finding the reasons of the exceptions (data validation errors) coming during the data submission.

Involved in debugging and troubleshooting.

Involved in performing database related operations.

Handled Oracle Apps Purchasing for procurement (requisitions, Purchase orders, Invoices, payments)

#### **Environment:**

Informatica, Oracle Apps, Sql, Plsql, Appworx, Linux, Service-now.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from JNTU College of Engineering, Kakinada in 2013

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Git, SVN			
Tomcat, Nginx			
MAVEN			
Jenkins			
ORACLE, MYSQL			
Service now, Jira, ZenHub			
Linux, Windows			
SHELL			
CHEF			
SonarQube			
AMAZON Web Services			
dockers and kubernetes			

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

## **Projects**

Project Title: Shared Sourcing Service

Client: GE

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Dec 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda, Glacier, VPC, EBS, RDS, ELB, Autoscaling, Cloudfront, Cloudwatch), GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Chef, Docker, Kubernetes, Unix/Linux environment

Project Details: Shared Sourcing Services is an Indirect Purchasing System for all GE businesses which is expanded over 180+ regions, , it will receive feed files from Souring ERPs Requisitioning and purchasing are performed within in operating units while invoice matching and supplier payment (accounts payables) is performed with the legacy/ERP. Currently I am being part of Cloud Migration which includes application, database migration from Oracle ERP to AWS Cloud

Project Title: Transport Management System

Client: Clorox

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Mar 2018 - Nov 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: AWS EC2, ELB, S3, Java/J2EE, Cloud watch, RDS, VPC, R53, Linux, Cloud Formation, Auto scaling, Chef, GIT, Maven, Jenkins, JIRA.

Project Details: Transport management, roster and routing solution. It reduces transport costs and improves operational efficiency. It improves vehicle utilization, driver utilization and route planning. Increase control of transport through better management reporting. TMS takes the HRMS data of the organization and provides GUI to add the geo-codes, in time and out time of the employees. It provides interface to add all the available facilities, vendors, vehicles and drivers. I-TMS generates optimum pickup and drop routes based on the geo-codes, estimated time of arrival of the employees, and calculates the estimated distance, time and cost. It provides interface to assign the generated routes to the vendors, vehicles and drivers. Also provides interface to modify the generated routes.

Project Title: Consumer Portfolio Analysis- Support

Client: GE Capital America Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2017 - Mar 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Consumer-IRIS basically deals with financial lending products, basically in two segments i.e. Mortgage & Non-Mortgage lending products. Mortgage consist home loans where a certain mortgage is pledged with GECA. Non-mortgage lending products consist of personal loans, credit cards and auto loans.

All the transactions which occur daily at the country level are consolidated at the end of every month for each product using their legacy system. This data is fed into the CIRIS data mart monthly once and month closing happens after this data is validated.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time